[Waco] Garden Clinic Garden Club records., Inclusive: 1951-2001, Bulk: 1956-1959, 1980-1994
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Garden Clinic Garden Club records.
Inclusive: 1951-2001, Bulk: 1956-1959, 1980-1994
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3638
[Waco] Garden Clinic Garden Club
1 document box and 2 oversize document boxes.
The [Waco] Garden Clinic Garden Club records contain minutes, constitutions, booklets, awards, certificates, journals, and scrapbooks collected by the Garden Clinic Garden Club.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Poor.
Biography/Profile
The Garden Clinic Garden Club was established in Waco, Texas, as an evening garden club that catered to business women who were unable to attend daytime meetings. They were colloquially known as the “business womens’ garden club.” During the preliminary meetings in the summer of 1951, the organization’s name, flower (amaranthus), and color (flame) were chosen. The first club meeting was held on 1951 September 11 with fourteen charter members. That October, it was decided that the club would limit their membership to twenty-four women. Members participated in home gardening, floral arrangement, and community service.
The Garden Clinic Garden Club’s projects have included “Planning and Maintaining Home Gardens,” “Plant Texas,” “Planting, Landscaping and Maintaining Home Gardens—and Water Conservation,” and “Supplying parakeets and cages for Crippled Children’s Hospital, Waco, Texas.” Members of the Garden Clinic Garden Club participated in various flower shows, conventions, and festivals across the state of Texas, including the annual Flower Show, the State Convention of Garden Clubs, and the Waco Council Garden Center Spring Festival. In 1954 March at the second annual Flower Show, themed "Gardens of the United Nations," the Garden Clinic won a tri-colored award for their floral exhibit inspired by Indonesia. On 1954 June 15, the Garden Clinic appeared on a local television program that advertised the activities of Waco’s garden clubs. The Garden Clinic Garden Club also helped to raise funds for the Garden Council Building in 1956. During that same year, they donated a tree to the Garden Council’s Memorial Tree Fund.
The Garden Clinic Garden Club was associated with the Waco Council of Garden Clubs, the National Council of State Garden Clubs, Inc., and Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., District V. The club was part of a large network of garden clubs in Waco during the twentieth century.
Scope and Content
The [Waco] Garden Clinic Garden Club records consist of materials collected by the Garden Clinic Garden Club during the twentieth century and the very early twenty-first century. Series I, Club Records, contains minutes, a journal, and a report on the club's involvement with intermediate education. Series II, Awards and Accolades, contains certificates, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and copies of certificates. Series III, Publicity/Press, contains scrapbooks.
Arrangement
This collection was partially processed. It resided in two document boxes and was in five series: I. Club Documents, II. Club Awards, III. Yearbooks, IV. Scrapbooks, and V. Intermediate Garden Club for Students. The first series was organized chronologically.
The collection is currently divided into three series: I. Club Records, II. Awards and Accolades, and III. Publicity/Press. The first series is arranged chronologically. The second series is arranged topically and then chronologically. The third series contains four scrapbooks in original order.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3638. Acquired 2005-05-06
Index Terms
Places
Waco (Tex.) -- History -- 20th Century.
Subjects
Awards.; Certificates.; Gardening -- Texas -- McLennan County.; Gardening -- Texas -- Waco -- Societies, etc.; Social participation -- Texas -- Waco.; Women -- Societies and clubs -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Minutes (Records); Scrapbooks.
- Club Records, 1953-1982; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Poor.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains minutes, club activities, a journal, and annual reports generated by the Garden Clinic Garden Club. The series is in poor condition.
  - Minutes and Records, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and Records, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and Records, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and Records, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and Records, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and Records, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and Records, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - President Beth Morris's Journal, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Intermediate Garden Club for Students, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Awards and Accolades, 1976-2001; 2
  General condition: Good.
  This series contains awards, certificates, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets. The series is in good condition.
  - Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1994-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - District V of Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - District V of Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - District V of Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1994-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Copies of District V, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Copies of District V, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings, Pamphlets, and Awards, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Publicity/Press, 1951-1988; 3
  This series contains four scrapbooks. The series is in poor condition.
  - Scrapbook (1 of 5), 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook (2 of 5), 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook (3 of 5), 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook (4 of 5), 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook (5 of 5), 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook (1 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook (2 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook (3 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1988 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Item 2)